[BERTHOLDT]
Heads up. She's back.
Good.
[REINER grunts]
Oh, no!
[ARMIN] No! They're
getting away with Eren!
[Grunts]
Ride! Let the Titans chase you!
All squads, follow my lead!
Do what? Erwin,
you conniving bastard!
You're using us as bait again?
It's the only way!
You've fought well as MP's.
Now give your all as soldiers!
The Armored Titan must
be stopped before he takes Eren.
Failure is not an option!
♪ Opening Song ♪
Reiner's too slow!
We've got him!
I won't hesitate this time.
I'll kill them
without a thought.
If Ymir feels
like getting in the way,
so much the worse for her.
This ends here and now.
I swear it!
[Coughing]
[BERTHOLDT]
Christa!
[CHRISTA gasps]
Ymir.
Ymir!
[Coughs]
Christa--
[Coughing]
No--Historia,
I'm sorry about eating you.
You're uh, probably pissed.
[Coughs]
Wha-What is this? I--
What's going on? Talk to me!
We came to rescue you and Er--
Just shut up!
I don't need rescuing.
Things have changed.
I'm with Reiner
and Bertholdt now.
Like it or not,
you're coming with us.
There's no future
inside the walls.
[Panting]
Here me out
for a second, okay?
Life outside isn't as bad
as you think, believe me.
For starters, there's no one
saying the world woulda be
a better place
if you'd never been born.
Yeah, I don't think Titans
would say much either way.
They'd be too busy
trying to devour me!
We've all got flaws!
They're not so bad if
you'd just give 'em a break!
It's complicated, all right?
Get off your high horse!
Ymir! I don't know what's
going on in your mind,
but you're not making
any sense! Come on!
What did Reiner
and Bertholdt say?
You're doing this
against your will,
they threatened you!
It's the opposite, actually.
I'm right, aren't I? Let go!
Whatever they've got
on you, I don't care!
We can fight them!
Put the past behind you!
What matters is right now!
I'm here! I will
always be your ally!
[BERTHOLDT]
Ymir!
Look. In case you
haven't noticed,
the Scouts are closing in.
If we'd left earlier,
there might've been
a decent chance
of outrunning them.
Going back for Christa
was your idea.
You forced us. Remember that.
We waited.
For what? Damn it, Ymir!
What the hell
did we do this for?
You can't have
a change of heart!
You want her
to rot inside the walls?
Does that seem
acceptable to you now?
Don't be a fool! Think!
Let go! Don't listen to him!
I can't!
I wish I could.
I'm sorry, sweetie.
I know you think
I did this for you.
But at the end of the day,
I did it for me.
A long time ago I stole
the Power of the Titans
from one of their comrades.
Not much I can do against them.
Sooner or later, I'm screwed.
But, they said if
I cooperate, hand you over,
maybe I've got
a shot at leniency.
Maybe my crime gets overlooked.
You're crucial to the Church.
You know the truth
about the walls!
[Gasps]
[CHRISTA] My family?
That's it, isn't it?
[YMIR]
Sure. Why not?
[YMIR] When this world
started going to hell
I thought to myself,
"couldn't hurt to have
a bargaining chip
in my back pocket."
The castle's as close
to death as I ever wanna get.
Whole experience
traumatized me.
Gave me perspective.
If I have to play
dirty to stay alive,
then I have to play dirty.
Pathetic, yeah. Doesn't make
me the ideal friend.
Like I said, though,
I didn't do this for you.
You deserve better,
but there it is.
I need you.
Please save me, Historia!
[CHRISTA]
Well, like I said.
[Gasps]
I'm here, and I will
always be your ally!
[YMIR sobs]
[grunts, yells]
[MALE SOLDIER 36A screams]
[Roars]
[MIKASA grunts]
Reiner! Protect us!
[YMIR TITAN roars]
[MIKASA] All right, then.
Looks like Ymir goes first!
--[MIKASA bellows]
--[CHRISTA] Mikasa, no!
You're not going to kill Ymir.
That all depends on her.
What'll it be?
She can step aside
or she can die. Her choice.
That's not fair!
She'll die if she doesn't
go along with what Reiner
and Bertholdt tell her to do.
She's screwed either way!
[Grunts] Listen,
there're only so many lives
I can give a damn about.
Cruel, but that's the world our
enemies gave us six years ago.
Sorry. I don't have
any heartstrings left
for you to tug on. If you
want compassion, move on.
You want fair, tough shit.
Time's wasting.
Pick your side, Christa.
Eren? Or the bitch
I'm gonna kill?
[Roars]
[CHRISTA]
Ymir, stop!
Look at her face! She means it!
Don't make a move!
[EREN grunts]
Quit struggling!
It's not going to help!
[JEAN] Good luck talking sense
into that one, Bertholdt.
When something lights
a fire under him, that's it.
Getting Eren to
calm down's a lost cause.
Take my word for it.
I've been on the receiving
end more than you have.
What do you say
we teach him patience?
Come on. Show yourself.
Give him back! Right now!
[CONNY] Guys, really? This is
some kind of joke, right?
No way this is you.
You've been lying
to us this whole time?
We were supposed to be comrades!
They still are! This is all
just a misunderstanding!
[JEAN]
Where d'you think you're going?
You can't keep running forever.
We're not gonna let
that happen. Rat bastards.
Through thick and thin
we slept under the same roof
as soldiers for three years.
Matter of fact, the
positions you could sleep in
were an art from, Bertholdt.
I'm not kidding.
We all loved waking up
to see your contortions
in the morning.
Used to predict
the weather with 'em.
How'd you do it, Bertholdt?
Must not've had
a care in the world.
Lying beside your victims,
yet you slept like a log.
Was it all just an act to you?
What about the way
we used to talk about
surviving this together?
About growing old, looking back
on the worst of it over drinks.
Remember? Was that all bullshit?
Answer me!
Go on. What was the point?
What were you trying to do?
[MIKASA]
It doesn't matter anymore.
Shut up and focus on
opening the traitor's neck.
Hesitate for a moment
and we forfeit Eren.
Who cares
what they pretended to be?
This was their choice.
No! You're wrong!
Who chooses to be this? Tell me!
What d'you think I am?
Huh? What?
You think this is
what we aspired to be?
People loathe us.
And why wouldn't they?
We're monsters!
We deserve to die
for the things we've done.
We're lost. We could live
a thousand years
and never again know peace.
Try to imagine that darkness.
The only light was
our brief time as soldiers.
It was never a lie!
Do you understand?
We're not who we said we were,
but it wasn't an act!
We genuinely thought
of you as our friends!
I'm not stupid. I know I have
no right to ask forgiveness,
but please. I beg of you.
If we were comrades,
someone find us.
Give him back.
I won't ask again.
I'm sorry. I can't.
[MIKASA gasps]
[BERTHOLDT]
One of you has to do it.
One of you has to stain
your hands with my blood!
[HANNES] Guys! Get down
from there and take cover!
What the hell's Erwin doing?
He's off his rocker! Look!
The lunatic's leading
the Titans straight for us!
[REINER TITAN growls lowly]
Jump, damn you!
Get the hell out of there!
Squadrons break!
Make the Titans scatter!
[REINER TITAN grunts]
[CHRISTA grunts]
[BOTH groan]
--[CHRISTA screams]
--[YMIR] Historia!
[Roars]
[JEAN]
What's going on? Is this hell?
[ERWIN]
Not yet. But it will be.
All soldiers charge!
[CONNY]
Huh?
[ERWIN] We've come
to the moment of truth!
Mankind's fate is decided now!
There is no future in which
we reclaim these lands
without Eren--
and there never will be!
Go! Recover Eren from
the Armored Titan and retreat!
Your heart and soul
to the cause!
[CONNY]
Mikasa, wait!
[SCOUTS yell]
[MALE SOLDIER 33B]
This is madness.
The Scouts have taken one
too many hits to the skull.
--Look out!
--Huh?
[MALE SOLDIER 33B screams]
[EREN]
What's happening out there?
Ugh! If only I could see!
[REINER] I can't move. 'Less I
can shake these Titans,
it'll only get worse.
Okay, then.
Heads up, Bertholdt.
Brace yourself!
That's right.
Just a little more!
It's working!
His hands are down!
Now's our chance!
Uh, Mikasa? You can see
those Titans, right?
I mean, I get it, you're strong.
But that's one hell of a mess.
Slipping through
isn't gonna be easy.
Advance!
[MIKASA gasps]
[ALL gasp]
[MALE SOLDIER 36C]
Commander Erwin!
I said advance, goddamn it!
Eren's right in front
of you! Do not falter!
[Gasps]
[SCOUTS yell]
[MALE SOLDIER 36D screams]
[MALE SOLDIER 36E and 36F scream]
--[MALE SOLDIER 36G screams]
--[MALE SOLDIER 36H yells]
[MALE SOLDIER 36I screams]
[ALL yell]
[MIKASA grunts]
[EREN yells muffled]
[Screams]
[JEAN]
Mikasa!
You piece of shit!
Get your hands off her!
[MALE SOLDIER 36K, 36L yell]
We've come too far
to give up now.
Wearegoing home.
And Eren is coming with us.
[EREN]
No. This is all on me.
People are dying
because I got caught!
[ARMIN]
Bertholdt!
[EREN]
Armin?
[ARMIN]
That's the irony, really.
If you can't let it go
it's not worth holding on to.
[ERWIN]
Advance!
[ARMIN] Think. What is it
I have to let go of?
My life? Or something else?
[Gasps]
[ARMIN]
So, you're okay with this?
Leaving your friend behind
to face the music?
[BERTHOLDT gasps]
[REINER gasps]
I guess Annie
was weighing you down?
D'you know where she is?
Way up north in the Utopia
District. Being tortured.
[grunts]
[ARMIN] The silent treatment
only goes so far.
The body may heal, but her
screams are an object lesson
on the limits of endurance.
Oh, don't worry,
they're taking special care
she doesn't die...
or get a moment's rest.
So many methods, so little time.
Mustn't waste a
prize specimen like Annie.
She's too precious.
Shut your mouth, hell spawn!
I'll kill you!
[ERWIN grunts]
[Growls]
[ERWIN]
All soldiers, retreat!
[Roars]
[Yells]
[CHRISTA]
I did it.
I actually killed one.
You all right?
Get away from her!
What the hell
were you trying to pull?
We're leaving!
Yeah, couldn't you go for
some grub right about now?
You don't understand!
Let me down!
Please!
[BOTH]
Huh?
Reiner and Bertholdt
are going to kill Ymir
unless we both agree
to go back with them!
She'll only be free
if she hands me over!
I'd already decided
to let that happen.
Are you nuts?
What if it's a trick?
[CHRISTA]
It's not! Let me go!
Conny's right!
Whatever she said, it's a lie!
Don't listen to her!
This doesn't make sense.
Why would someone
who fought tooth and nail
to save your life just
turn you over to the enemy?
What's the end game?
[CONNY] The only time Ymir
bothers to make an effort
is when you're in danger.
I don't know what kind
of trouble she's in,
but for now just calm down
till we know more.
[SASHA] Exactly. Either way,
we can't stick around.
Whatever Ymir needs you for,
I'm sure you won't
be much good to her dead!
[CHRISTA gasps]
Damn straight. Even I
could figure that one out.
[BOTH gasp]
[SASHA yells]
[ALL gasp]
[SCOUTS yell]
He's tossing Titans now?
That son of a bitch
has gone berserk!
[REINER TITAN roars]
[BOTH gasp]
[ARMIN]
Eren! Mikasa!
Eren.
[Whimpers]
[Grunts and gasps]
♪ Closing Song ♪